The radiance of the night shines through my window
but the path to immortality is long.
The Eight Views and Nine-Bend Streams are desolate.
Living beings question the miseries of the world over a jar of wine.
Forget about Nirvana and rebirth,
I will break through the waves with my own flesh and blood.
The heavens are vast, so what if I was born mediocre ?
I stare at the Dao in my moments of madness
as the storm rages just below.
I've been thinking about life and death in my dreams.
I've unsheathed my sword to ask the immortals
why the world is a-changing.
Heaven and earth reveals its poignant truths.
Swallow the Four Seas and the Eight Wastelands,
experience all the vicissitudes of life in an instant.
I will defy the light in the sky
to continue to write a new chapter for all things in the three realms of existence.
Just a thought separates mortal from immortal.
Transform your insignificant body into light.
The hardships of the journey
will temper this young man's heart.
If I become a Renegade Immortal, will I hesitate to fight the heavens ?
Renegade Immortal\NSubtitles by Bonobosubs\Nhttps://discord.gg/Ceckd4pdVA
I, Wang Lin, have a principle.
Purple Division\NHeavenly Fate Sect
If one doesn't mess with me,
I won't mess with them.
But if someone dares to mess with me
I will destroy them !
You disrespectful brat !
How dare you act recklessly
on this joyous day of our Heavenly Fate Sect !?
Earth Shard !
You've provoked me twice now.
If I don't kill you,
I am not Wang Lin.
Demonic flames  !
What ?!
How is this possible ?!
Seventh Brother,
this is Master’s birthday.
There are many fellow cultivators here !
Don't act recklessly !
Outsiders of the Heavenly Fate Sect
will not interfere
in this internal strife.
Seventh Brother,
sit down !
The competition
isn't today.
You don't get to decide
whether we do it today
or not !
Heaven and Earth Mantra of Freedom !
This is Master's birthday.
You wouldn't dare to kill me !
You won't kill me !
Wang Lin,
you dared to kill a direct disciple !?
He's too bold !
Indeed...
It's your turn now.
Wang Lin broke the sect rules
by killing a disciple !
Where are the Disciplinary Elders ?
Whoever stands in my way
is my enemy !
This...
You guys !
Fourth Sister !
I already repaid
the favor I owed you.
Give me a good reason
to intervene.
Fine !
I wanted to save this for the competition...
But we will
settle this now with a fight to the death !
Master actually planted a demon seed inside him !?
That's unfair !
This is bad !
What is that !?
God Slaying Chariot,
activate !
Stop this at once !
What are you even fighting for ?
You didn't even let me finish my wine...
Greetings
Uncle Chi Lie.
Calling me Uncle won't save you.
You forcefully used the demon seed before it was ready.
Your Master said
that you are banned from participating
in the competition.
No...
Impossible !
I cultivated 1000 years for this !
Disciple
obeys...
Little guy,
without the demon seed
you would have won.
Not bad !
The position of Violet Son of Tian Yun is vacant.
Your Master
has high hopes for you.
The Juniors of the Violet Division just caused a ruckus,
and ruined the mood.
I hope everyone will forgive us.
Tomorrow,
my Senior Brother the All-Seer will give a lecture on the Dao.
I hope everyone will benefit from it
and make this event worth your time.
So that ghost was an Ancient Demon,
it gave me the same feeling as an Ancient God.
What was that spell ?
Seventh Brother !
It seems the title Son of Tian Yun is within your grasp.
Let me toast to your success in advance.
This is the Teleportation spell I promised.
I originally planned to give it to you
after Master's birthday.
Besides the Teleportation Spell, this jade slip
also contains a Forbidden Spell created by Master.
I give them both to you
as an apology for what happened a month ago.
Young friend !
The younger generation is formidable !
Fellow cultivator,
let's toast to your success !
Purple Forest Pavilion
This Teleportation spell is very powerful.
I crossed 10 000 li
in an instant.
The Forbidden Spell recorded in the jade slip,
the Nine Cycles Celestial Refining Tactic,
is used to transform celestial spiritual energy
into golden celestial spiritual energy.
I painstakingly circulated it for 5 hours
but I'm only at the third cycle.
Unfortunately, the two types of celestial spiritual energy are incompatible.
I will store it in my left hand for now.
The day of the lecture
has finally arrived.
Main Palace of the\NHeavenly Fate Sect
I heard the Violet Division is the weakest
and lacks talent.
It seems it's true.
Keep your voice down !
Silence.
Late stage Soul Transformation...
Peak Late stage Soul Transformation...
Half-step Ascendant ?
On planet Tian Yun, just the disciples
of any single division
could sweep planet Suzaku.
We pay respects to the All-Seer !
We pay respects to Master !
I am the All-Seer.
I cultivated for tens of thousands of years
and glimpsed at the Dao of the heavens.
In this lecture on the Dao,
I wish to share my cultivation insights with you all.
I didn't expect you to send an avatar,
it's an honor.
How could I not come
to your once in 10 000 years birthday !
This little weasel...
I arrived in a hurry
so couldn't prepare any good gifts.
I know you like things with seven colors.
Sun Zhongan\NEnvoy of the Cultivation Alliance
This sword is an upper middle grade celestial artifact.
Its golden color
should suit your taste.
Kunpeng Zi,
your cultivation has made great progress lately.
I bestow this sword to you.
Thank you Master !
Your attitude
still hasn't changed !
This is a Star-Marked Weasel,
a pet that loves Ancient Gods.
Could it have sensed the faint Ancient God aura on me ?
The Dao of Heavenly Fate
is infinitely profound.
Fellow cultivators,
if you have doubts, please ask me.
The Heaveny Art
is about seeing the 99 cycles as one origin.
The first step
from Qi Condensation
all the way to Ascendant
is cultivation.
The second step
from Illusory Yin and Corporeal Yang
to the 3 stages of Nirvana Shattering
is the transition between cultivation and the Dao.
And the third step
is the true essence of the Dao.
Sadly, even I haven't comprehended it yet.
My Dao of Heavenly Fate is:
if that if you are fated,
you can achieve anything.
But if you are not fated,
10 000 years of cultivation
will not amount to anything.
If what the All-Seer says is true
then I haven't even finished the first step.
But does the third step
even exist ?
Wang Lin,
do you have any questions ?
Master,
disciple indeed has a question.
Speak up.
On the path of cultivation
I have heard of 3 terms.
Cultivating immortality,
cultivating truth,
cultivating the Dao.
Why does Master only refer to it as cultivating the Dao
and not the others ?
A good question.
The Celestials are gone.
Cultivating immortality came from the ancient celestials.
The Celestial Realm was the holy land of cultivation back then.
Hence the saying "cultivating immortality".
The "truth" in "cultivating truth"
is the source of everything.
After the Celestial Realm shattered,
cultivators were like trees without roots.
Homeless and drifting in the void.
That's how "cultivating truth" became the core of cultivation.
And now,
both immortality and truth are things of the past.
What we seek is the Dao.
But this kind of Dao
is not the Dao of the heavens.
How can you cultivate the Dao but not follow the Dao of the heavens ?
Then what is the Dao ?
The "Dao" in "cultivating the Dao"
is a path, a direction.
Because we don't know what the third step is,
we are looking for a path to reach it.
This
is what the "Dao" in "cultivating the Dao" means.
Wang Lin,
does that answer your question ?
Disciple wonders
if the third step even exists.
30 000 years ago,
I met a person
who had already reached the third step.
Unfortunately, he only appeared for a short time
and then disappeared.
Master,
disciple also has a question.
disciple has a question.
3 days later
Is everyone satisfied
after these 3 days of lecture ?
Old man All-Seer,
how could I not come to your birthday !?
It's Sword Saint Ling Tianhou !
It's Ling Tianhou !
It's him !
Why did he come ?
Why is Ling Tianhou here ?
Disciples,
come pay respects to Senior All-Seer !
Old man All-Seer,
so...
why aren't you welcoming me ?
How could I not ?
I was just preparing to demonstrate a middle grade celestial spell.
You
have come at the right time.
Now,
I will target you with this celestial spell
and let everyone present observe it.
What do you think ?
Why not ?
Fellow cultivators,
this is the middle grade Celestial Guidance Spell.
It was used by ancient celestials
to send cultivators like us to the Celestial Realm.
Everyone,
pay close attention.
Celestial Gate,
open !
This spell...
it's disrupting my celestial spiritual energy.
Somehow the golden celestial spiritual energy is not affected !
Guidance !
All-Seer,
you...
I am the Celestial Realm's Eternal Envoy,
I am here to guide you cultivators from lower realms.
Old man All-Seer...
The Celestial Realm is no more !
Where did your Celestial Guidance Spell
send all my disciples !?
Sword Saint, don't worry.
They will return here in 3 days.
At that time, I will need to borrow a few of your disciples
to ask them what they saw.
Qilin,
come back !
Old man All-Seer,
3 months from now
bring the people you have chosen
to the East Demon Spirit Sea.
I have one more thing
that I want everyone to see.
Among my 7 divisions of the Heavenly Fate Sect,
the Yellow and Violet divisions
still don't have Sons of Tian Yun.
Today
is the day of the competition
for the Seven Sons of Tian Yun.
Are you all
ready to begin ?
I've been walking this path for endless years
just to catch a glimpse of your silhouette.
Is it the compass of fate
that wrote this outcome for us ?
The heavens want to erase your existence,
that's the obsession guiding me.
Is this the path to uncover
truths from falsehoods ?
In a world of murk and shadow,
only the flame of truth can light the way.
Look at them all,
being carried by the waves.
being drowned.
I don't want to believe in whoever decides fate,
I will let the world refine my soul.
So what if I become an Immortal and defy the heavens ?
I will fight.
I'll break through the abyss of despair
to finally learn who I really am.
My body is stained by the bloody color of slaughter,
I embrace this obsession.
I won't glance back at the wasteland I left behind.
Even if this suffering shatters my soul
and I'm reborn countless times in hell,
I'll still fight.
It's hard to avoid loneliness
when you are above everyone else.
Can a moth that has witnessed the flames of a Suzaku
be afraid of a firefly ?